tmx.com 2018-11-17

# TMX - Terms of Use

This privacy policy sets out the information gathering and dissemination practices of TMX Group Limited ("TMX Group") and its affiliates and subsidiaries (collectively, the "TMX" or "we") in the use of TMX's websites (collectively, "the Websites"). By using the Websites, you are consenting to this privacy policy and the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information by TMX as outlined in this privacy policy. If this privacy policy is not acceptable to you, please do not submit any of your personal information.

We may update this privacy policy from time to time and you are responsible for periodically reviewing the most current version of this privacy policy on the Websites. Your continued use of the Websites or submission of information will be deemed your conclusive acceptance of the updated privacy policy.

In this Privacy Policy, the phrase "Service Providers" includes, but is not limited to, any licensors, suppliers, information providers or other third parties that provide or administer, from time to time, any data, information, content, application, tool or service to TMX.

#### Collecting, Using and Disclosing Information

This privacy policy describes our policies regarding the collection, use and disclosure of the personal information that we (or our Service Providers on our behalf) collect about you on the Websites such as your name, address, phone number, fax number, e-mail address or payment information. We may collect this information when you subscribe to, or sign your company up for, certain services, tools or features that we provide, when you register for seminars or other programs that we offer, when you fill out forms made available through the Websites, when you enter a promotion or contest, when you complete a survey, when you e-mail us with general inquiries or with your comments or suggestions, when you make a purchase or otherwise in connection with your use of the Websites. We will limit the personal information we collect to what we need for the purposes for which it was collected, and will use such personal information for such purposes. We may also use personal information we collect to provide you with information on products, services and events that we or third parties offer that we believe may be of interest to you. If we wish to use your personal information for any other purpose, we will obtain your consent before using the information.

#### Storing of Information and Restricting Access

We may store your personal information (in encrypted form where we believe it to be highly sensitive) in electronic databases or e-mail boxes hosted by us or our Service Providers, for periods of time and with safeguards that we believe are reasonable depending on the nature and sensitivity of the information. Access to the information is restricted in accordance with our security protocols.

Certain features on the Websites are password-protected to prevent unauthorized access. You are responsible for the confidentiality and use of such passwords.

Due to the nature of Internet communications and evolving technologies, TMX cannot provide assurance that the personal information we collect will remain free from loss, interception, misuse or alteration by third parties and TMX and its Service Providers shall have no liability for any loss, interception, misuse or alteration.

#### Automatic Collection of Information

In some cases, we may collect information about you that may or may not be personally-identifiable. Examples of this type of information include your Internet protocol (IP) address, the type of Internet browser you are using, the type of computer operating system you are using, the pages viewed on the Websites, Website navigation path, duration of access, the Website elements or forms you click or view, and the advertisement or domain name of the website from which you linked to the Websites. The collection, use, disclosure and storage of such information will be in accordance with this privacy policy, including for the purpose of optimizing Website user experience.

#### Cookies and Other Website Tools

Some pages on the Websites use a technology called "cookies". A cookie is a token that a server gives to your browser when you access a website. Cookies are capable of storing many types of data. Cookies may be placed by TMX or a third party. Cookies help provide additional functionality to the Websites or help provide and analyze Website traffic and usage information. Usage data can be stored in these cookies, in order to record your preferences, log-in details and settings for future visits, and in some cases to personalize the advertisements displayed on the Websites. For instance, our server may set a cookie that keeps you from having to enter a password more than once during a visit to one of the Websites. In all cases in which cookies are used, we will not collect personally-identifiable information except with your permission.

In addition to the cookies we set during your use of the Websites, additional cookies may be set, where applicable, by third party providers when you visit our website. This occurs because we have commissioned third parties to collect information for us, for example for statistical usage analysis (e.g. as part of Google Analytics); it also occurs because our sites contain content or advertisements of third parties. Where required, your browser connects, for the purpose of accessing such third party content, directly with the servers of the third party providers, thus enabling those providers to place their own cookies on your end device.

We use Google Analytics on the Websites, a web analytics tool from Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. Google Analytics uses information obtained by the cookies it sets about your use of the Websites to statistically evaluate your use of our website for us, to create reports on website activities and to provide further services related to the website and the internet usage for us. This information may be transmitted to a server in the USA and stored there. Where required by European or other jurisdictions' privacy laws, we use an anonymization tool in order to mask your IP address before it is transmitted outside of your jurisdiction. Even if your IP address is transmitted to Google (where privacy laws permit this), the IP address will not be combined with other data from Google. Please note that Google Analytics information may be disclosed to marketing agency partners that use the data to optimize marketing campaigns.

Clear GIFs (also known as web bugs, beacons, tracking pixels or tags) are small graphic images which are placed on a website. We use Clear GIFs to collect statistical usage data about the Websites, functions or other elements of a website. Clear GIFs also enable us to determine, for example, whether users come to the Websites via an advertisement placed by us on another website. We use the data collected in this way for statistical purposes in order to analyze and improve the Websites and our marketing campaigns.

With most Internet browsers, you can erase cookies from your computer hard drive, block all cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored. Please refer to your browser instructions or help screen to learn more about these functions. You can deactivate the Google Analytics function with a browser add-on, which you can download at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>. To do this you must install that browser add-on. This will prevent the analysis information from being sent to Google.

#### Releasing Information

We may provide your personal information to other persons but only if:

  * we have your consent;
  * we provide the information to Service Providers who assist us in serving you and who have agreed to appropriate contractual provisions regarding the protection of personal information in accordance with applicable law; or
  * we are required to do so by law, regulation or court order.

Your personal information may be transferred (or otherwise made available) to our affiliates and other third parties who provide services on our behalf. For example, we use Service Providers to assist us process, store and secure data. This may include sending email or other communications using their online services. Our Service Providers are given the information they need to perform their designated functions, and are not authorized to use or disclose personal information for their own purposes. Your personal information may be maintained and processed by us, our affiliates and other third party Service Providers in other jurisdictions. In the event personal information is transferred to another jurisdiction, it will be subject to the laws of that jurisdiction and may be disclosed to or accessed by the courts, law enforcement and governmental authorities in accordance with those laws.

#### Respecting and Responding to Your Privacy Concerns

You have the option to refuse or withdraw consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information, and we will respect your choices. If you wish to exercise this option or if you have any questions or enquiries with respect to our privacy policies or procedures, please send a written request to: Chief Privacy Officer, TMX Group, 100 Adelaide St. West, Toronto, ON, M5H 1S3. We will investigate and respond to your concerns about any aspect of our handling of your information.

BY USING THE WEBSITES, YOU ACKNOWLEDGE THAT YOU HAVE READ THIS PRIVACY POLICY, UNDERSTAND IT AND AGREE TO ALL OF THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY.

Updated June 19, 2018
